<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>podcast on devmedeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.com/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in podcast on devmedeiros</description>
    <image>
      <title>devmedeiros</title>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 18:15:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.com/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Review - Machine Learning Guide</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/podcast-review-mlg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 18:15:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/podcast-review-mlg/</guid>
      <description>A review about the podcast Machine Learning Guide</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/mlg-capa_4H_gyNxIV.jpg#center" alt="Machine Learning Guide Podcast Cover"  />
</p>
<p>The show is presented by Tyler Renelle from Depth, since 2021 it has been redone to update the content. The podcast offers a <a href="https://ocdevel.com/mlg/resources">resource</a> list where you can find all of the books, courses, and sites mentioned during the podcast. It&rsquo;s a great podcast for anyone who is learning about machine learning, it can be useful for a complete beginner, an enthusiast, or someone who is looking to further even more on this topic.</p>
<p>The show starts by talking about what is <em>data science</em>, how it relates to <em>machine learning</em> and <em>artificial intelligence</em>. It also talks about the first attempts humans had made to create AI, with some examples coming from as early as the 13th century.</p>
<p>I like that the show talks about concepts of machine learning in a different way than I&rsquo;m used to. When people are talking about machine learning, as a Statistician, I always feel that I understand what people are talking about, except I never knew the keywords they were using. What machine learning engineers might call <em>features</em> I was taught as <em>variable</em>, so I got confused when talking to friends about machine learning when they came from a different background as me (e.g. computer science). This is one of the reasons why I like the podcast so much because it talks about deep details about every machine learning concept so if it is talking about something that I already know I can now make that connection.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
