<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dev_Medeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dev_Medeiros</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 19:23:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Feature Selection</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-06-14-feature-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 19:23:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-06-14-feature-selection/</guid>
      <description>What is feature selection? Feature selection is the process of finding pertinent features and eliminating unnecessary, redundant, or noisy data. It can be useful to help the training process be faster and it can also avoid overfitting. According to Munson and Caruana, the goal of feature selection is to identify the feature set that best balances the risks of having too few features with the risks of having too many features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Challenge - Churn Rate</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-05-30-churn-rate-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:49:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-05-30-churn-rate-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools used:&lt;/strong&gt; Python, seaborn, scikit-learn, imbalanced-learn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category:&lt;/strong&gt; Data Analysis, Machine Learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX/UI for Business Intelligence Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-29-ux-power-bi-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 11:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-29-ux-power-bi-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>What is UX/UI? UX is the acronym for User Experience, it is a recent concept about making design decisions while thinking about the user experience. The UX designer needs to be concerned about whether their product is easy to use and intuitive, making changes to it whenever necessary to suit the user&amp;rsquo;s needs.
UI stands for User Interface. It is everything involved in the interaction of the user and the product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling with CEAP</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-17-storytelling-with-ceap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 10:08:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-17-storytelling-with-ceap/</guid>
      <description>The Dataset CEAP stands for Cota para o Exercício da Atividade Parlamentar, in English, Exercise of Parliamentary Activity from Brazil. The quota is a monthly amount that can be used by the deputy/senator to defray typical expenses of the exercise of the parliamentary mandate.
The monthly amounts don&amp;rsquo;t accumulate over the months. Another important thing is Senators in Brazil have an 8-year mandate, and there are elections every 4 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehending the P Value</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-12-comprehending-the-p-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 17:58:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-12-comprehending-the-p-value/</guid>
      <description>What is the p-value? In statistics, we have hypothesis tests, which are made to decide whether to reject or not reject the null hypothesis. Some examples of hypothesis testing are Neyman-Pearson, Shapiro-Wilk, Student&amp;rsquo;s T-test, and others.
All hypothesis tests have a test statistic specific to them. And this statistic is used to evaluate the test, but this task can be tiring even with the use of computers because most software does not return the comparison statistic as an output, only the sample statistic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alura Skimo - Power BI Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-03-08-alura-skimo-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:34:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-03-08-alura-skimo-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>Tools used: Power BI, Figma, SQL
Category: Dashboard
This dashboard is the last out of three from the second Alura Challenge BI.
Alura Skimo is interested in analyzing their sales data, to help with this I made this dashboard. It’s composed of three pages. The first one presents a summary of all the main measures you’ll find in the dashboard, filtered for the most recent month. On this first page, you can also rest your mouse cursor over a measure and it’ll show a small plot with the historical series with a tendency line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alura Food - Power BI Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-02-26-alura-food-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 12:16:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-02-26-alura-food-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>Tools used: Power BI, Google Sheets, Figma
Category: Dashboard
This dashboard is the second of three that I&#39;m making in the following weeks as part of the second Alura Challenge BI.
Alura Food is interested in expanding its business by entering the Indian market. To do so, the company asked to calculate measures to help them make a better decision.
First of all, I merged the datasets and cleaned the data through Power BI, translated a few texts from English to Portuguese through Google Sheets, and converted the meals price from their respective currency value to BRL (Brazillian Currency).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alura Films - Power BI Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-02-17-alura-films-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 18:42:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-02-17-alura-films-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>Tools used: Power BI, Google Sheets, Figma
Category: Dashboard
This dashboard is the first of three that I&#39;ll be making in the following weeks as part of the second Alura Challenge BI.
The objective of this dashboard is to help find the best selection for an upcoming movie.
With this in mind, I explored in the first tab a little summary about the movies in the database, with this you can get a general view of our data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Review - Machine Learning Guide</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-01-24-podcast-review-mlg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 18:15:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-01-24-podcast-review-mlg/</guid>
      <description>The show is presented by Tyler Renelle from Depth, since 2021 it has been redone to update the content. The podcast offers a resource list where you can find all of the books, courses, and sites mentioned during the podcast. It&amp;rsquo;s a great podcast for anyone who is learning about machine learning, it can be useful for a complete beginner, an enthusiast, or someone who is looking to further even more on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive Analysis of Amazon Top 50 Bestselling Books 2009 - 2019</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-12-28-amazon-top-50-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 14:55:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-12-28-amazon-top-50-books/</guid>
      <description>Recently I finished an Alura course named Python for Data Science and I want to put what I learned into practice, to do so I&amp;rsquo;ll make a descriptive analysis on this dataset Amazon Top 50 Bestselling Books 2009 - 2019. It contains 550 books and the data has been categorized as fiction and non-fiction by Goodreads. All of the code can be found here.
I started checking the first five observations from the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python seaborn Package Guide</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-07-seaborn-package-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 15:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-07-seaborn-package-guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m learning data visualization in Python and I see myself as a &amp;lsquo;hands on&amp;rsquo; learner, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be reproducing some basic plots using seaborn package that you can use as a reference everytime you need to fresh up your memory.
At first is required that the packages are properly imported, after that I load the iris dataset.
import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns import matplotlib.pyplot as plt url = &amp;#34;https://git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have COVID Impacted California Traffic Collisions?</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-02-sql-california-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 17:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-02-sql-california-traffic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools used:&lt;/strong&gt; SQL, R&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category:&lt;/strong&gt; Data Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview on data.table R Package</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-10-27-data-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 09:41:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-10-27-data-table/</guid>
      <description>The data.table package is one of the fastest packages for data manipulation, currently, it is even faster than pandas and dplyr 1. data.table syntax is dt[i, j, by], where:
i is used to subset rows j is used to subset columns by is used to subset groups, like GROUP BY from SQL You can read it out loud as2:
Take dt, subset/reorder rows using i, then calculate j, grouped by by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackjack Simulation</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-10-24-blackjack-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 20:43:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-10-24-blackjack-simulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools used:&lt;/strong&gt; R, ggplot, Shiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category:&lt;/strong&gt; Simulation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis of Fake News vs Real News</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-10-12-fakenews-sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:47:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-10-12-fakenews-sentiment/</guid>
      <description>I want to tackle sentiment analysis using R in a simple way, just to get me started. With this in mind we begin loading all the packages we&amp;rsquo;ll be using.
library(readr) library(dplyr) library(tidytext) library(tokenizers) library(stopwords) library(ggplot2) Then we need to load our dataset. This data comes from Kaggle Fake and real news dataset.
Fake &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;#39;~/fakenews/Fake.csv&amp;#39;) True &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;#39;~/fakenews/True.csv&amp;#39;) I want to merge the two datasets, but first we need to create a new column that will tell me where the data came from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
