<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>review on devmedeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.com/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review on devmedeiros</description>
    <image>
      <title>devmedeiros</title>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 20:51:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Up with the Latest in Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/keeping-up-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 20:51:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/keeping-up-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>How to keep up with the latest discoveries in Machine Learning Models and academic research.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every day new research regarding Machine Learning is being published, and it may seem impossible to keep up with all the new models and applications that people are using. So I want to talk about my two favorite ways to keep up with new research and know about what people are working on.</p>
<h2 id="1---two-minute-papers">1 - Two Minute Papers</h2>
<p>This YouTube <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TwoMinutePapers">channel</a> is my favorite one to keep up with new research regarding Machine Learning. They are always releasing new videos talking about papers showing what researchers have just published, focusing mainly on the results, but always linking the original paper so you can read more about it.</p>
<p>Two Minute Papers have been covering the OpenAI discoveries for quite some time now, I remember seeing videos about what ChatGPT could do, before it was open to the public, and it compared it with previous versions. So you can see the progress being made, even if you miss the older videos, they always make a comparison with previous versions when available.</p>
<p>The videos are kept in an approachable language, so even beginners can understand the main points. Additionally, the channel also makes the videos entertaining, so it&rsquo;s easy to keep watching and stack on more knowledge.</p>
<h2 id="2---papers-with-code">2 - Papers with Code</h2>
<p><a href="paperswithcode.com">Papers with Code</a> is more than a website that just indexes papers. It makes it easier to find papers with code about Machine Learning, linking the papers, the source code, and even datasets.</p>
<p>If you want to learn about the state-of-the-art of a specific topic in Machine Learning you can browse between tasks, for example, if you are looking for more information about Natural Language Processing, you can choose a specific task, like Named Entity Recognition, then you&rsquo;ll be able to see the current benchmarks, according to database, the best model, the model paper and source code. It also links the databases used to research the specific task you choose and it links libraries that you can use to apply the models.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Better Graphs</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/choose-the-best-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 08:01:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/choose-the-best-graph/</guid>
      <description>Choosing the best graph or plot can be a hard task, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Learning how to make better visualizations come with study and practice, today I want to talk about sources you can use to guide you into making better graphs and other data visualizations in general.</p>
<h2 id="from-data-to-viz">From Data to Viz</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/416qeWj.png" alt="infograph showing different possibilities for choosing a plot"  />
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.data-to-viz.com/">From Data to Viz</a> brings a lot of tools to help navigate the data visualization world. In the website <code>Explore</code> tab you are faced with an interactive infographic that helps you pick a plot, you can choose between: <code>numeric</code>, <code>categoric</code>, <code>numeric&amp;categoric</code>, <code>maps</code>, <code>network</code>, and <code>time series</code>. But it doesn&rsquo;t only show plots that would be good for your type of data, it also shows a description explaining the plot and common mistakes people make when using that specific plot.</p>
<p>At the end of each branch from the infographic, there is also a <code>story</code> link, where you can read about an implementation of that type of plot using real-world data.</p>
<p>And in the case, you are just starting and don&rsquo;t know many terms or are unsure if your data contains <code>too many</code> or <code>few</code> points when you rest your mouse over the options nodes you&rsquo;ll be able to see a description with an example table representing what that means.</p>
<p>By heading to the <code>Caveats</code> tab you&rsquo;re able to see a collection of caveats, you can filter them by:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Improvement:</strong> all caveats that will suggest some sort of improvement on plots.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Misleading:</strong> some plots may be misleading by omitting some information, may it be sample size or how proportionally different two categories are. By reading this you&rsquo;ll be able to spot bad practices that lead to confusion or manipulation.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This website also provides links to <strong>Python</strong> and <strong>R</strong> galleries where you can get code snippets to reproduce these plots.</p>
<p>If you prefer to learn by looking at what not to do, you should check out <a href="https://viz.wtf/">WTF Visualizations</a>. It showcases bad visualizations that don&rsquo;t make sense or are somehow misleading.</p>
<p>There you&rsquo;ll find several pie plots that don&rsquo;t add up to 100%, area graphs where the numbers don&rsquo;t match the area, and just straight-up manipulation like the example below.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/d8bcf748d564125312aeba4001b96df5/tumblr_qzg4n3nfJY1sgh0voo1_640.jpg#center"
         alt="a donut graph showing &#39;yes&#39; as a majority while it represents 10%, and &#39;no&#39; as a minority while it represents 90%"/> <figcaption>
            <p>piechart from <a href="https://viz.wtf/">WTF Visualizations</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Review - Machine Learning Guide</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/podcast-review-mlg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 18:15:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/podcast-review-mlg/</guid>
      <description>A review about the podcast Machine Learning Guide</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/mlg-capa_4H_gyNxIV.jpg#center" alt="Machine Learning Guide Podcast Cover"  />
</p>
<p>The show is presented by Tyler Renelle from Depth, since 2021 it has been redone to update the content. The podcast offers a <a href="https://ocdevel.com/mlg/resources">resource</a> list where you can find all of the books, courses, and sites mentioned during the podcast. It&rsquo;s a great podcast for anyone who is learning about machine learning, it can be useful for a complete beginner, an enthusiast, or someone who is looking to further even more on this topic.</p>
<p>The show starts by talking about what is <em>data science</em>, how it relates to <em>machine learning</em> and <em>artificial intelligence</em>. It also talks about the first attempts humans had made to create AI, with some examples coming from as early as the 13th century.</p>
<p>I like that the show talks about concepts of machine learning in a different way than I&rsquo;m used to. When people are talking about machine learning, as a Statistician, I always feel that I understand what people are talking about, except I never knew the keywords they were using. What machine learning engineers might call <em>features</em> I was taught as <em>variable</em>, so I got confused when talking to friends about machine learning when they came from a different background as me (e.g. computer science). This is one of the reasons why I like the podcast so much because it talks about deep details about every machine learning concept so if it is talking about something that I already know I can now make that connection.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
