<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerBI on Dev_Medeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.github.io/tags/powerbi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerBI on Dev_Medeiros</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:34:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.github.io/tags/powerbi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alura Skimo - Power BI Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2022-03-08-alura-skimo-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 13:34:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2022-03-08-alura-skimo-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>Tools used: Power BI, Figma, SQL
Category: Dashboard
 This dashboard is the last out of three from the second Alura Challenge BI.
 Alura Skimo is interested in analyzing their sales data, to help with this I made this dashboard. It’s composed of three pages. The first one presents a summary of all the main measures you’ll find in the dashboard, filtered for the most recent month. On this first page, you can also rest your mouse cursor over a measure and it’ll show a small plot with the historical series with a tendency line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alura Food - Power BI Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2022-02-26-alura-food-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 12:16:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2022-02-26-alura-food-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>Tools used: Power BI, Google Sheets, Figma
Category: Dashboard
 This dashboard is the second of three that I&#39;m making in the following weeks as part of the second Alura Challenge BI.
 Alura Food is interested in expanding its business by entering the Indian market. To do so, the company asked to calculate measures to help them make a better decision.
First of all, I merged the datasets and cleaned the data through Power BI, translated a few texts from English to Portuguese through Google Sheets, and converted the meals price from their respective currency value to BRL (Brazillian Currency).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alura Films - Power BI Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2022-02-17-alura-films-powerbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 18:42:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2022-02-17-alura-films-powerbi/</guid>
      <description>Tools used: Power BI, Google Sheets, Figma
Category: Dashboard
 This dashboard is the first of three that I&#39;ll be making in the following weeks as part of the second Alura Challenge BI.
 The objective of this dashboard is to help find the best selection for an upcoming movie.
With this in mind, I explored in the first tab a little summary about the movies in the database, with this you can get a general view of our data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Beautiful Power BI Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2021-10-15-beautiful-power-bi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 12:08:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.github.io/2021-10-15-beautiful-power-bi/</guid>
      <description>Here are 5 Tips to improve your Power BI Dashboards.
1- Color scheme Unless you are working with a particular company that has defined rules on branding and how their logos and pamphlets should be displayed, deciding which colors to use will be a big part of your dashboard designing.
When starting, it may not be easy to choose a color scheme with confidence. You may find yourself always going for monochromatic with black and white.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
