<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>data visualization on devmedeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.com/tags/data-visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data visualization on devmedeiros</description>
    <image>
      <title>devmedeiros</title>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 22:30:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.com/tags/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to use Word clouds?</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/how-to-use-word-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 22:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/how-to-use-word-clouds/</guid>
      <description>Word clouds are a popular data visualization tool for analyzing texts, but they need to be presented clearly for the message to be understood.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Word clouds are a popular data visualization tool for analyzing texts, comment boxes, and reviews. And it&rsquo;s not popular for no reason, it is an efficient visualization to show the opinion of a group of people in a summarized way, but it is not always presented effectively. So, here are some points to pay attention to when presenting the best word cloud you can.</p>
<h2 id="1--removing-common-and-irrelevant-words">1- Removing common and irrelevant words</h2>
<p>One of the most common words in the English language is the article &ldquo;the&rdquo;. This is not surprising, given that it is essential for forming sentences, but despite being fundamental, when we think in terms of how it helps to explain the theme or idea of a sentence, it does not contribute to it at all. These articles and other common words are called <strong>stopwords</strong>.</p>
<p>So, whenever we work with word clouds, it&rsquo;s important to remove these stopwords to make it clear what your theme is and to reduce information pollution.</p>
<h2 id="2--simplicity-over-complexity">2- Simplicity over complexity</h2>
<p>When working with visual presentations, it&rsquo;s common to want to do something extravagant that catches people&rsquo;s attention, but sometimes complex visualizations can distract people from the story you want to tell and make it difficult to understand your message.</p>
<h2 id="3--segment-your-data">3- Segment your data</h2>
<p>One of the most common uses of word clouds is in customer reviews and company evaluations (such as NPS), in these cases, where we have different &ldquo;types&rdquo; of customers, it&rsquo;s expected that they have very different behaviors, a satisfied or happy customer will have different comments from one who is dissatisfied. So, if you make only one-word cloud without segmenting your data, you may find a word cloud that means nothing more than &ldquo;many people mentioned this&rdquo;.</p>
<p>By segmenting the data by customer ratings or by detractors and promoters, you can identify what customers who are happy with your service are saying and contrast it with what those who are dissatisfied are saying, and identify areas for improvement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Better Graphs</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/choose-the-best-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 08:01:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/choose-the-best-graph/</guid>
      <description>Choosing the best graph or plot can be a hard task, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Learning how to make better visualizations come with study and practice, today I want to talk about sources you can use to guide you into making better graphs and other data visualizations in general.</p>
<h2 id="from-data-to-viz">From Data to Viz</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/416qeWj.png" alt="infograph showing different possibilities for choosing a plot"  />
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.data-to-viz.com/">From Data to Viz</a> brings a lot of tools to help navigate the data visualization world. In the website <code>Explore</code> tab you are faced with an interactive infographic that helps you pick a plot, you can choose between: <code>numeric</code>, <code>categoric</code>, <code>numeric&amp;categoric</code>, <code>maps</code>, <code>network</code>, and <code>time series</code>. But it doesn&rsquo;t only show plots that would be good for your type of data, it also shows a description explaining the plot and common mistakes people make when using that specific plot.</p>
<p>At the end of each branch from the infographic, there is also a <code>story</code> link, where you can read about an implementation of that type of plot using real-world data.</p>
<p>And in the case, you are just starting and don&rsquo;t know many terms or are unsure if your data contains <code>too many</code> or <code>few</code> points when you rest your mouse over the options nodes you&rsquo;ll be able to see a description with an example table representing what that means.</p>
<p>By heading to the <code>Caveats</code> tab you&rsquo;re able to see a collection of caveats, you can filter them by:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Improvement:</strong> all caveats that will suggest some sort of improvement on plots.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Misleading:</strong> some plots may be misleading by omitting some information, may it be sample size or how proportionally different two categories are. By reading this you&rsquo;ll be able to spot bad practices that lead to confusion or manipulation.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This website also provides links to <strong>Python</strong> and <strong>R</strong> galleries where you can get code snippets to reproduce these plots.</p>
<p>If you prefer to learn by looking at what not to do, you should check out <a href="https://viz.wtf/">WTF Visualizations</a>. It showcases bad visualizations that don&rsquo;t make sense or are somehow misleading.</p>
<p>There you&rsquo;ll find several pie plots that don&rsquo;t add up to 100%, area graphs where the numbers don&rsquo;t match the area, and just straight-up manipulation like the example below.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/d8bcf748d564125312aeba4001b96df5/tumblr_qzg4n3nfJY1sgh0voo1_640.jpg#center"
         alt="a donut graph showing &#39;yes&#39; as a majority while it represents 10%, and &#39;no&#39; as a minority while it represents 90%"/> <figcaption>
            <p>piechart from <a href="https://viz.wtf/">WTF Visualizations</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Score Classification App</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/credit-score-classification-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 17:17:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/credit-score-classification-app/</guid>
      <description>Using Streamlit to make a web app that classifies your credit score using Python</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="project-overview">Project Overview</h2>
<p>This project showcase a data science life cycle, where I clean and prepare the dataset, use feature engineering, machine learning, deploy, and data visualization.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/data-science-cycle_QZwyHaXsP.png?ik-sdk-version=javascript-1.4.3&amp;updatedAt=1659975338736#center" alt="data science cycle of this project in a diagram"  />
</p>
<p>The dataset comes from <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/datasets/parisrohan/credit-score-classification?select=train.csv">kaggle</a>, it has a lot of information about a person&rsquo;s credit and bank details, but it also has a lot of typos, missing data, and censored data. This dataset needed cleaning and also needed some feature engineering, I needed to mutate some features, so they could be read by the model. Thus when presented with categorical data I needed to identify if it was ordinal or nominal, if it was an ordinal variable then it would be mapped to sequential numbers otherwise I&rsquo;d make a dummy. For <em>yes</em> and <em>no</em> variables I choose to make just one dummy, but for types of loans I made one dummy for each loan type and if someone didn&rsquo;t have a loan they simply get 0 on all loan type features. I talk about the process of cleaning and feature engineering on this dataset <a href="/post/data-cleaning-credit-score/">here</a>.</p>
<p>Then I needed a machine learning model that I could predict a person&rsquo;s credit score based on some features. To decide which features I was going to use I based my decision on what is commonly used among real companies, and I also choose variables that I thought made sense. I ended up with the following features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Age</li>
<li>Annual income</li>
<li>Number of bank accounts</li>
<li>Number of credit cards</li>
<li>Number of delayed payments</li>
<li>Credit card utilization ratio</li>
<li>Total EMI paid monthly</li>
<li>Credit history age in months</li>
<li>Loans</li>
<li>Missed any payment in the last 12 months</li>
<li>Paid minimum amount on at least one credit card</li>
</ul>
<p>With the features ready, I moved on to making the model, I decided to use a simple Random Forest, for now, I do intend to work on making this model better, but in this first instance, I wanted to focus on making the streamlit app.</p>
<p>After I finished the model I serialized it and the scaler using the <code>pickle</code> package. To deploy the model and build a visualization I used <a href="https://streamlit.io/">streamlit</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/33239902/183321842-be97fb04-f00b-4b62-8e6e-2b53d25335a0.gif" alt="a gif showing how the streamlit credit score app works"  />
</p>
<p>In this app, you can fill out a form or just select one of the three default profiles given to see how the model evaluates each person&rsquo;s credit score. It also presents how certain the model was by displaying a pie graph with the probability (in percentage) of each credit score group the answers fit. It also shows how much each feature counts towards your credit score, according to this model. You can see the app live <a href="https://devmedeiros-credit-score-classification-appstreamlit-app-fcakrl.streamlitapp.com/">here</a>.</p>
<hr>
<p>All of the code is available at my GitHub <a href="https://github.com/devmedeiros/credit-score-classification-app">repository</a>. Besides the code, there you&rsquo;ll find the documentation, the original and treated data (all the stages of treatment), all the requirements for building this project, and how to run it locally.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alura Challenge BI 2</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/alura-challenge-bi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 19:23:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/alura-challenge-bi-2/</guid>
      <description>Alura hosted a four-week Challenge BI, where participants needed to make 3 dashboards</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Alura Challenge BI 2 was a four-week event where we&rsquo;re challenged to make <em>Business Intelligence</em> dashboards according to the request of three made-up companies. During the event I made this three dashboard using Power BI, you can look at the source file of all dashboards at my <a href="https://github.com/devmedeiros/Alura-Challenge-BI-2">repo</a>.</p>
<br />
<style>
	nav {
		display: block;
	}

	.nav {
		display: -ms-flexbox;
		display: ruby;
		-ms-flex-wrap: wrap;
		flex-wrap: wrap;
		padding-left: 0;
		margin-bottom: 1em;
		list-style: none;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-item {
		margin-bottom: 0;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-link {
		border: solid #e9ecef;
		border-top-left-radius: 0.25rem;
		border-top-right-radius: 0.25rem;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-link:focus,
	.nav-tabs .nav-link:hover {
		border-color: #e9ecef #e9ecef #dee2e6;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-link.disabled {
		color: #6c757d;
		background-color: transparent;
		border-color: transparent;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-item.show .nav-link,
	.nav-tabs .nav-link.active {
		color: #495057;
		background-color: #fff;
		border-color: #dee2e6 #dee2e6 #fff;
	}

	.nav-fill .nav-item {
		-ms-flex: 1 1 auto;
		flex: 1 1 auto;
		text-align: center;
	}

	.nav-tabs .dropdown-menu {
		margin-top: -1px;
		border-top-left-radius: 0;
		border-top-right-radius: 0;
	}

	.nav-justified .nav-item {
		-ms-flex-preferred-size: 0;
		flex-basis: 0;
		-ms-flex-positive: 1;
		flex-grow: 1;
		text-align: center;
	}

	.nav-link {
		display: block;
		padding: 0.5rem 1rem;
	}

	.nav-link:focus,
	.nav-link:hover {
		text-decoration: none;
	}

	.nav-link.disabled {
		color: #6c757d;
		pointer-events: none;
		cursor: default;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-link {
		border: 1px solid #e9ecef;
		border-top-left-radius: 0.25rem;
		border-top-right-radius: 0.25rem;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-link:focus,
	.nav-tabs .nav-link:hover {
		border-color: #e9ecef #e9ecef #dee2e6;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-link.disabled {
		color: #6c757d;
		background-color: transparent;
		border-color: transparent;
	}

	.nav-tabs .nav-item.show .nav-link,
	.nav-tabs .nav-link.active {
		color: black;
		background-color: #F5F5F5;
		border-color: #dee2e6 #dee2e6 #fff;
	}

	.nav-pills .nav-link {
		border-radius: 0.25rem;
	}

	.nav-pills .nav-link.active,
	.nav-pills .show>.nav-link {
		color: #fff;
		background-color: #007bff;
	}

	.navbar-nav .nav-link {
		padding-right: 0;
		padding-left: 0;
	}

	.navbar-expand .navbar-nav .nav-link {
		padding-right: 0.5rem;
		padding-left: 0.5rem;
	}

	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .nav-link {
		color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.5);
	}

	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .nav-link:focus,
	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .nav-link:hover {
		color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.7);
	}

	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .nav-link.disabled {
		color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.3);
	}

	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .active>.nav-link,
	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .nav-link.active,
	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .nav-link.show,
	.navbar-light .navbar-nav .show>.nav-link {
		color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.9);
	}

	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .nav-link {
		color: rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.5);
	}

	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .nav-link:focus,
	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .nav-link:hover {
		color: rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.75);
	}

	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .nav-link.disabled {
		color: rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.25);
	}

	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .active>.nav-link,
	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .nav-link.active,
	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .nav-link.show,
	.navbar-dark .navbar-nav .show>.nav-link {
		color: #fff;
	}
</style>

<nav>
	<div class="nav nav-tabs" id="nav-tab" role="tablist">

		
		
		
		

		

		<a class="nav-item nav-link  active "
		   id="nav-aecdbf" data-toggle="tab" href="#aecdbf"
		   role="tab" aria-controls="nav-home" aria-selected="true">Alura Films</a>

		

		<a class="nav-item nav-link "
		   id="nav-cefbda" data-toggle="tab" href="#cefbda"
		   role="tab" aria-controls="nav-home" aria-selected="true">Alura Food</a>

		

		<a class="nav-item nav-link "
		   id="nav-cfedba" data-toggle="tab" href="#cfedba"
		   role="tab" aria-controls="nav-home" aria-selected="true">Alura Skimó</a>

		

	</div>
</nav>

<div class="tab-content" id="nav-tab-content">

	
<style>
	.tab-content>.tab-pane {
		display: none;
	}

	.tab-content>.active {
		display: block;
	}

	.fade {
		transition: opacity 0.15s linear;
	}
	.fade:not(.show) {
		opacity: 0;
	  }
	  .modal.fade .modal-dialog {
		transition: -webkit-transform 0.3s ease-out;
		transition: transform 0.3s ease-out;
		transition: transform 0.3s ease-out, -webkit-transform 0.3s ease-out;
		-webkit-transform: translate(0, -50px);
		transform: translate(0, -50px);
	  }
	  .modal-backdrop.fade {
		opacity: 0;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item {
		opacity: 0;
		transition-property: opacity;
		-webkit-transform: none;
		transform: none;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item-next.carousel-item-left,
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item-prev.carousel-item-right,
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item.active {
		z-index: 1;
		opacity: 1;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .active.carousel-item-left,
	  .carousel-fade .active.carousel-item-right {
		z-index: 0;
		opacity: 0;
		transition: opacity 0s 0.6s;
	  }
</style>






<div class="tab-pane fade show active " id="aecdbf" role="tabpanel" aria-labelledby="nav-1">

	

<p>The objective of this dashboard is to help find the best selection for an upcoming movie.</p>

<iframe title="Relatório Alura Films" width="100%" height="450" src="https://app.powerbi.com/view?r=eyJrIjoiZTllNjE2ZTQtNjdkMy00OGI4LTllNTAtM2RhNGE2YWU4YmZlIiwidCI6IjI2ZjA4NzIyLTFjOWUtNGVkZS1iN2VkLThhMmI3N2ZmM2Q5YyJ9&pageName=ReportSection11c983afd307f2fa2f9a" frameborder="0" allowFullScreen="true"></iframe>

<p>With this in mind, I explored in the first tab a little summary about the movies in the database, with this you can get a general view of our data. The second tab is displayed the IMDB and Meta Score of the movies. I also created a measure to show how much both measurements agree. A score of 100 means <strong>doesn't agree at all</strong> and 0 means <strong>completely agree</strong>, the agreeable score was 9.48.</p>
<p>Our third tab shows information about the movie stars, the top 10 actors with the highest movie gross revenue, and the top 10 actors with the biggest movie count.</p>
<p>The fourth tab presents the distribution of gross revenue by how many different genres a movie has. It also shows how many movies have a given genre, for example, <strong>Drama</strong> is the most popular choice for movie genre, with 72% of movies in the dataset. At last, this tab also shows the mean gross revenue by genre.</p>
<p>The fifth and last tab shows a bit of information about the Brazillian Parental Guide and shows the average Meta Score for movies by the parental guide certification. It also shows how much gross revenue, on average, each parental guide certification earned.</p>



</div>
<style>
	.tab-content>.tab-pane {
		display: none;
	}

	.tab-content>.active {
		display: block;
	}

	.fade {
		transition: opacity 0.15s linear;
	}
	.fade:not(.show) {
		opacity: 0;
	  }
	  .modal.fade .modal-dialog {
		transition: -webkit-transform 0.3s ease-out;
		transition: transform 0.3s ease-out;
		transition: transform 0.3s ease-out, -webkit-transform 0.3s ease-out;
		-webkit-transform: translate(0, -50px);
		transform: translate(0, -50px);
	  }
	  .modal-backdrop.fade {
		opacity: 0;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item {
		opacity: 0;
		transition-property: opacity;
		-webkit-transform: none;
		transform: none;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item-next.carousel-item-left,
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item-prev.carousel-item-right,
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item.active {
		z-index: 1;
		opacity: 1;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .active.carousel-item-left,
	  .carousel-fade .active.carousel-item-right {
		z-index: 0;
		opacity: 0;
		transition: opacity 0s 0.6s;
	  }
</style>






<div class="tab-pane fade show " id="cefbda" role="tabpanel" aria-labelledby="nav-1">

	

<p><strong>Alura Food</strong> is interested in expanding its business by entering the Indian market. To do so, the company asked to calculate measures to help them make a better decision.</p>

<iframe title="Relatório Alura Food" width="100%" height="450" src="https://app.powerbi.com/view?r=eyJrIjoiNGEzMTQzMGYtNzFhNC00YjcyLThiMDMtMGE2YTMzMDRhODFiIiwidCI6IjI2ZjA4NzIyLTFjOWUtNGVkZS1iN2VkLThhMmI3N2ZmM2Q5YyJ9&pageName=ReportSection" frameborder="0" allowFullScreen="true"></iframe>

<p>First of all, I merged the datasets and cleaned the data through Power BI, translated a few texts from English to Portuguese through Google Sheets, and converted the meals price from their respective currency value to BRL (Brazillian Currency). Finally, I used Figma to make the background, including images and titles.</p>
<p>In this project, I opted to used a single page to display all the requested information as I believe it makes it easier to analyze the data.</p>
<p>Most restaurants in this Indian market don't offer online delivery, with just 19.21% having it. The average rating for the restaurants is 3.72 out of a maximum of 5, the rating is also presented as text, with a <em>Muito Bom</em> (Very Good) being a score over 4.</p>
<p>The average price of a meal per person is around R$ 39.48 (around USD 7.65). And there are 9577 different restaurants in the dataset, of which 3968, specialize in North Indian cuisine. New Delhi is, by far, the most popular choice to open a restaurant with 5473, the second closest city is Gurgaon, with 1118 restaurants.</p>



</div>
<style>
	.tab-content>.tab-pane {
		display: none;
	}

	.tab-content>.active {
		display: block;
	}

	.fade {
		transition: opacity 0.15s linear;
	}
	.fade:not(.show) {
		opacity: 0;
	  }
	  .modal.fade .modal-dialog {
		transition: -webkit-transform 0.3s ease-out;
		transition: transform 0.3s ease-out;
		transition: transform 0.3s ease-out, -webkit-transform 0.3s ease-out;
		-webkit-transform: translate(0, -50px);
		transform: translate(0, -50px);
	  }
	  .modal-backdrop.fade {
		opacity: 0;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item {
		opacity: 0;
		transition-property: opacity;
		-webkit-transform: none;
		transform: none;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item-next.carousel-item-left,
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item-prev.carousel-item-right,
	  .carousel-fade .carousel-item.active {
		z-index: 1;
		opacity: 1;
	  }
	  .carousel-fade .active.carousel-item-left,
	  .carousel-fade .active.carousel-item-right {
		z-index: 0;
		opacity: 0;
		transition: opacity 0s 0.6s;
	  }
</style>






<div class="tab-pane fade show " id="cfedba" role="tabpanel" aria-labelledby="nav-1">

	

<p><strong>Alura Skimo</strong> is interested in analyzing their sales data, to help with this I made this dashboard.</p>

<iframe title="Relatório Alura Skimo" width="100%" height="450" src="https://app.powerbi.com/view?r=eyJrIjoiNTllYjJmODItYzQxNC00ZmEzLTk5ZGMtZDgzNzY2NDM2ZGMxIiwidCI6IjI2ZjA4NzIyLTFjOWUtNGVkZS1iN2VkLThhMmI3N2ZmM2Q5YyJ9" frameborder="0" allowFullScreen="true"></iframe>

<p>It’s composed of three pages. The first one presents a summary of all the main measures you’ll find in the dashboard, filtered for the most recent month. On this first page, you can also rest your mouse cursor over a measure and it’ll show a small plot with the historical series with a tendency line.</p>
<p>Moving on to the next page, you can see all the information about the products sold by <strong>Alura Skimo</strong>. You can filter the data by ice cream flavor, type of package, category, and product cost. It displayed the basic information about the products, along with a rank of the best-selling products and a couple of plots showing the sales by flavor and sales by category.</p>
<p>On the last page, you can find information about the salesperson from our company. It shows when they joined the company, how much is their cut, how much revenue they got and how many sales each one made, everything in the last year (2018).</p>
<p>This dashboard is complex next to the other two because our dataset came from SQL files. First, I had to create the database and load each SQL file into it, then all I had to do was load it on Power BI. At last, I did all the data cleaning and processing on it.</p>



</div>


</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX/UI for Business Intelligence Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-29-ux-power-bi-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 11:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-29-ux-power-bi-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>Defining UX/UI in the context of Bussiness Intelligence for Dashboards with examples</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-is-uxui">What is UX/UI?</h2>
<p>UX is the acronym for User Experience, it is a recent concept about making design decisions while thinking about the user experience. The UX designer needs to be concerned about whether their product is easy to use and intuitive, making changes to it whenever necessary to suit the user&rsquo;s needs.</p>
<p>UI stands for User Interface. It is everything involved in the interaction of the user and the product. The UI designer is responsible for developing interfaces, not only limited to the visual aspects but also ensuring that the interfaces are functional and usable and generally contribute to a good user experience.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-improve-the-experience-of-bi-dashboards">How to Improve the Experience of BI Dashboards?</h2>
<p>Many people see BI dashboards as web pages. This comes with some expectations. For example, most sites that have some navigation system use a top menu with buttons, a side menu (most common in Brazil being on the left, but in some countries, it is on the right), or a hamburger menu (the one we click on it and the options appear).</p>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/site_layout_C0BWt0-Rh.png?ik-sdk-version=javascript-1.4.3&amp;updatedAt=1651180441785"
         alt="Image with three website layouts, the first with a top navigation bar, the second with a left-side menu and the third with a sandwich menu"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Jaqueline Medeiros - All rights reserved</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>With this, a majority of people who use the dashboards expect to find navigation buttons and data segmentation (filter) in these places, in addition to other information such as logo and title.</p>
<h3 id="data-segmentation">Data Segmentation</h3>
<p>Also commonly called a data filter, it is a fundamental part of several dashboards, its positioning needs to be defined carefully, because if it is in a place that the user does not expect, it can prevent your dashboard from being used efficiently, in addition to maintaining a visual standard for everyone its filters help people more easily recognize what is and isn&rsquo;t a filter.</p>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/base_7_vbzsb9L.png?ik-sdk-version=javascript-1.4.3&amp;updatedAt=1651183332760"
         alt="Image with six filters, distributed in two columns, each one with three. One filter is for a city, the other is for a restaurant and the last one is for reservations? The only difference between them is the design, on the left they are consistent and on the right, each one has a unique design."/> 
</figure>

<p>You can and should use and experiment with different themes in your projects. What matters, when making it easier for users, is consistency, pick a model for your filters with the desired colors and all the graphic specifications that are of interest to you and use it in all filters, as this will help people quickly find it and recognize that it&rsquo;s a filter.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/borracha_Xwi_TYTHB.png?ik-sdk-version=javascript-1.4.3&amp;updatedAt=1651183773246#center" alt="Three filters with, city, restaurant and accept reservation? Where the city shows an eraser next to the title and the text Clear selections"  />
</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s common for people when they are reading something on the computer to position the mouse pointer where they are reading. For Power BI, this makes it easier for the user to find the clear data segmentation button because when hovering the mouse over the filter name, a rubber appears on the left side where the filter name is. If you use Power BI, you probably already knew that, but we can improve this by using something that the user already knows, which is the <strong>rubber</strong>, and create a button using it as an icon and make this button clear all filters at the same time. If you want to know how to make this button <a href="https://community.powerbi.com/t5/Desktop/Clear-All-Slicers-by-one-button-in-power-bi-desktop/m-p/494518">here</a>, in the Power BI forum, explains how.</p>
<p>This feature needs may be unnoticed at first. Regularly dashboard users don&rsquo;t realize which filters they have used or they use so many that they just want to be able to clear the selection faster and more efficiently, so this button makes the process easier.</p>
<h3 id="page-navigation">Page Navigation</h3>
<p>Power BI&rsquo;s native page navigation is not intuitive for most people and you may want to direct the navigation in a specific flow that facilitates understanding and contributes to the intended storytelling. In this case, we have the option to hide all the report tabs, except for the opening/home page. But what&rsquo;s the best way to direct the user to the other pages? Suppose your report is simple, you have an overview tab and another tab with a breakdown, a simple button would solve your problem, but if your report is extensive it may be unfeasible to put a button for each tab on all pages.</p>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/infografico_kQJe_yhQD.png?ik-sdk-version=javascript-1.4.3&amp;updatedAt=1651241421864"
         alt="A circle with four rectangles around it, a line connects the rectangles to the circle" width="100%"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Jaqueline Medeiros - All rights reserved</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>In this case, it might be interesting to consider having a home page that leads to all the other pages and placing a <code>home</code> or <code>back</code> button on them.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-improve-dashboards-interface">How to Improve Dashboards Interface?</h2>
<h3 id="prototyping-programs">Prototyping Programs</h3>
<p>Using a specific program to prototype your dashboard allows for greater artistic freedom compared to what Business Intelligence applications typically provide. Figma is a great tool for this, you can create advanced backgrounds and prototypes with amazing quality to use in your BI dashboards.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s an example of a dashboard I made a few months ago:</p>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/devmedeiros/Alura-Challenge-BI-2/main/Alura%20Food/alura%20food%20resume.png"
         alt="In the picture you can read the text: Overview of Indian Restaurants Market Dev_Medeiros City Restaurant Accepts Reservations? 19.21 % Restaurants with Online Delivery Average Rating 3.72 R$ 39.48 Average Price per Person 9577 Total Restaurants 5 Most Popular Cities Restaurants 5 Most Popular Cuisine"/> <figcaption>
            Panel with data
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The background of this panel was done completely in Figma, even some of the titles of the BI visuals.</p>
<figure>
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/devmedeiros/Alura-Challenge-BI-2/main/Alura%20Food/Alura%20Food.png"
         alt=" In the image you can read the text: Overview of Indian Restaurants Market Dev_Medeiros City Restaurant Accepts Reservations? % of Restaurants with Online Delivery Average Rating Average Price per Person Total Restaurants 5 Cities with the most Restaurants 5 Most Popular Cuisine"/> <figcaption>
            Background made in Figma
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>You can check out more <a href="/post/alura-challenge-bi-2">Power BI Dashboards</a> I made for Alura Challenge BI.</p>
<h3 id="figures-and-icons">Figures and Icons</h3>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://img.freepik.com/vetores-gratis/employees-dando-as-maos-e-ajudando-os-colegas-a-cliir-as-escadas_74855-5236.jpg?w%20=1380&amp;t=st=1651239796~exp=1651240396~hmac=1b2ab902322bbf8ce26e3bc83f602e69075fcc2e18f0afdc91a328c7942ba746#center"
         alt="Vector created by pch.vector - br.freepik.com"/> <figcaption>
            <p>Vector created by pch.vector - br.freepik.com</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Figures and icons when used correctly help make the panel stand out, and make it more eye-catching and beautiful. There are several ways to get images, if you or your team can&rsquo;t create them yourself there is the option of using online platforms that provide vectorized images. On these platforms, there are free options, which require some type of attribution, and premium (paid) options, which often do not need to attribute the author and have a higher quality.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://img.icons8.com/dusk/344/cash-register.png#center"
         alt="Cash register icon"/> <figcaption>
            <p>ICONS8 icon</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling with CEAP</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-17-storytelling-with-ceap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 10:08:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-04-17-storytelling-with-ceap/</guid>
      <description>The storytelling of how much each deputy/senator spends in Brazil</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-dataset">The Dataset</h2>
<p>CEAP stands for <em>Cota para o Exercício da Atividade Parlamentar</em>, in English, Exercise of Parliamentary Activity from Brazil. The quota is a monthly amount that can be used by the deputy/senator to defray typical expenses of the exercise of the parliamentary mandate.</p>
<p>The monthly amounts don&rsquo;t accumulate over the months. Another important thing is Senators in Brazil have an 8-year mandate, and there are elections every 4 years.</p>
<p>The main dataset is provided by the Brazilian government through the transparency portal.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> I gathered additional data to link the quota for each senator and federal unit.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
<h2 id="data-analysis">Data Analysis</h2>
<h3 id="total-amount-refunded-by-year">Total Amount Refunded by Year</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/devmedeiros/7DaysOfCode/main/img/refunded_year.jpg#center" alt="Bar plot with blue bars and green bars indicating election years, shows the total amount refunded by senators in Brazil"  />
</p>
<p>On the image above we can see how much was refunded by year. The year 2022 is the smallest because is not over yet. The data was collected on April 16, 2022.</p>
<p>There seems to be a trend to spend slightly less money on election years.</p>
<p>The first three years were the three lowest spending years, <strong>11.52M</strong>, <strong>11.61M</strong>, and <strong>10.64M</strong> from 2008 to 2010, respectively. This was probably because in the following years the expenses that could be refunded increased in 2011.</p>
<h3 id="top-highest-and-lowest-average-refunded-percentages-by-senators">Top Highest and Lowest Average Refunded Percentages by Senators</h3>
<p>These percentages represent the quota percentage a given senator refunded on average.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/devmedeiros/7DaysOfCode/main/img/senator_refund_highest_mean.jpg#center" alt="Horizontal bar plot with the 10 highest refundees, on average, senators"  />
</p>
<p>In the image above, it&rsquo;s seen highest refunded senators note that they’re all closed together, the highest refundee, on average, is João Capiberibe, using <strong>99.78%</strong> of his quota. On the lowest side (image below), it&rsquo;s presented the lowest use of the refund quota, on average. Nailde Panta, is the lowest refundee, on average, using just <strong>4.1%</strong> of her quota.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/devmedeiros/7DaysOfCode/main/img/senator_refund_lowest_mean.jpg#center" alt="Horizontal bar plot with the 10 lowest refundees, on average, senators"  />
</p>
<h3 id="expense-types-over-the-years">Expense Types Over the Years</h3>
<p>Here we can see that in the years 2008 to 2010 there wasn’t any refund by transport and private security services.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/devmedeiros/7DaysOfCode/main/img/expense_type_year.jpg#center" alt="Bar plot of expenses type refunded by the years 2008 to 2022"  />
</p>
<p>In 2008, the main expenses were publication of parliamentary activity (over <strong>R$ 7,000.00</strong>) and locomotion/accommodation (almost <strong>R$ 6,500.00</strong>). In the subsequent years, those expenses dropped in half, for the publications and to less than <strong>R$ 1,000.00</strong> for locomotion.</p>
<p>In 2013 and 2014 the expense of private security was the highest ever with over <strong>R$ 4,000.00</strong>. Probably due to protests in those years.</p>
<h2 id="to-learn-more">To learn more</h2>
<p>To learn how The Chamber of Deputies from Brazil works click <a href="https://www2.camara.leg.br/english">here</a>.</p>
<p>This is presentation is for learning purposes, from a challenge proposed by Alura #7DaysOfCode. In case you want to know what else can be done with the data, check the <a href="https://serenata.ai/en/">Serenata de Amor</a>. It&rsquo;s a Brazilian project that uses AI to track refunded requests by deputies.</p>
<p>See my code at my GitHub <a href="https://github.com/devmedeiros/7DaysOfCode">repo</a>, there you can also find a slide presentation, learn about how the data was cleaned, and know more about the next task from the challenge.</p>
<h3 id="references">References</h3>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://www12.senado.leg.br/transparencia/dados-abertos-transparencia/dados-abertos-ceaps">https://www12.senado.leg.br/transparencia/dados-abertos-transparencia/dados-abertos-ceaps</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lista_de_senadores_do_Brasil#Nova_Rep%C3%BAblica_(1987%E2%80%932023)">https://pt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lista_de_senadores_do_Brasil#Nova_Rep%C3%BAblica_(1987%E2%80%932023)</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p><a href="https://www2.camara.leg.br/legin/int/atomes/2009/atodamesa-43-21-maio-2009-588364-publicacaooriginal-112820-cd-mesa.html">https://www2.camara.leg.br/legin/int/atomes/2009/atodamesa-43-21-maio-2009-588364-publicacaooriginal-112820-cd-mesa.html</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA Amazon Top 50 Bestselling Books</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-12-28-amazon-top-50-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 14:55:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-12-28-amazon-top-50-books/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Data Analysis of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s top 50 bestselling books 2009 - 2019</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I finished an Alura course named <em>Python for Data Science</em> and I want to put what I learned into practice, to do so I&rsquo;ll make a descriptive analysis on this dataset <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/sootersaalu/amazon-top-50-bestselling-books-2009-2019"><strong>Amazon Top 50 Bestselling Books 2009 - 2019</strong></a>. It contains 550 books and the data has been categorized as fiction and non-fiction by Goodreads. All of the code can be found <a href="https://gist.github.com/devmedeiros/12813bebd78f7662966096e963ed0aa9">here</a>.</p>
<p>I started checking the first five observations from the dataset.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Name</th>
<th>Author</th>
<th>User Rating</th>
<th>Reviews</th>
<th>Price</th>
<th>Year</th>
<th>Genre</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>10-Day Green Smoothie Cleanse</td>
<td>JJ Smith</td>
<td>4.7</td>
<td>17350</td>
<td>8</td>
<td>2016</td>
<td>Non Fiction</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11/22/63: A Novel</td>
<td>Stephen King</td>
<td>4.6</td>
<td>2052</td>
<td>22</td>
<td>2011</td>
<td>Fiction</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>12 Rules for Life: An Antidote to Chaos</td>
<td>Jordan B. Peterson</td>
<td>4.7</td>
<td>18979</td>
<td>15</td>
<td>2018</td>
<td>Non Fiction</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1984 (Signet Classics)</td>
<td>George Orwell</td>
<td>4.7</td>
<td>21424</td>
<td>6</td>
<td>2017</td>
<td>Fiction</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5,000 Awesome Facts (About Everything!) (Natio&hellip;</td>
<td>National Geographic Kids</td>
<td>4.8</td>
<td>7665</td>
<td>12</td>
<td>2019</td>
<td>Non Fiction</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Here it&rsquo;s possible to see that the data has the <strong>Year</strong> in which the book was on the <em>top 50</em> list, it&rsquo;s <strong>Price</strong>, the average <strong>User Rating</strong>, total <strong>Reviews</strong>, <strong>Author</strong>, <strong>Name</strong> and lastly, <strong>Genre</strong>.</p>
<p>There are no null values in the dataset. And from 550 books there are 248 unique authors, so let&rsquo;s see which authors have had more books in the top 50 bestselling during this period.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Author</th>
<th>Number of Books</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Jeff Kinney</td>
<td>12</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gary Chapman</td>
<td>11</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Rick Riordan</td>
<td>11</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Suzanne Collins</td>
<td>11</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>American Psychological Association</td>
<td>10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dr. Seuss</td>
<td>9</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gallup</td>
<td>9</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Rob Elliott</td>
<td>8</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Stephen R. Covey</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Stephenie Meyer</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dav Pilkey</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bill O&rsquo;Reilly</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Eric Carle</td>
<td>7</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The author with more books in the top 50 list was Jeff Kinney, tied at second, with 11 books, was Gary Chapman, Rick Riordan, and Suzanne Collins. Tied at 9th is Stephen R. Covey, Stephenie Meyer, Dav Pilkey, Bill O&rsquo;Reilly, and Eric Carle, with 7 books.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/violing_ur_vmTFo02uK.jpg?updatedAt=1640708039606" alt="Violing plot of User Rating"  />
</p>
<p>With the violing plot, we can see how the user rating is concentrated and because our data is composed of bestsellers it makes sense that the user rating is mostly concentrated around 4.5 and 4.75.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/boxplot_year_reviews_Pa1YGMhj2z1.jpg?updatedAt=1640708039777" alt="Boxplot of Review Count by Year"  />
</p>
<p>This boxplot of reviews count by year shows that the variability increases through the years, having its peak at 2014 and gradually stabilizing. We can also see that in the first years, 2010 and 2011, there were more outliers in the data.</p>
<p>I wanted to look at the user rating and price by book genre. So I calculated these average values.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Genre</th>
<th>User Rating</th>
<th>Price</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Fiction</td>
<td>4.65</td>
<td>10.85</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Non Fiction</td>
<td>4.60</td>
<td>14.84</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The user rating average by genre seems to be similar just 0.05 difference, but the price has a bigger difference 10.85 for fiction and 14.84 for non-fiction books. To be sure that these differences are statistically significant I&rsquo;ll use the Mann-Whitney test.</p>
<p>The Mann-Whitney null hypothesis is that the samples have the same distribution, and in both cases, we reject the null hypothesis with a 95% confidence level. The p-value for the price data was 8.34e-08 and the user rating was 1.495e-07.</p>
<p>To visually show how different their distribution is we can take a look at the following plots.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/hist_price_qxT6fxEGQ.jpg?updatedAt=1640708039771" alt="Distribution for Book Price by Genre"  />
</p>
<p>The distribution for the price of fiction books is heavily inclined to the left and consistently diminishes as the price goes up. While the non-fiction books price starts high and becomes even higher, 120 and almost 140 occurrences in the first two categories, then it rapidly diminishes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/hist_ur_6YxOQ_Huz.jpg?updatedAt=1640708040024" alt="Distribution for User Rating by Genre"  />
</p>
<p>The distribution for the user rating by the fiction genre slowly increases, having its peek at around 4.8. And the distribution of the non-fiction genre has its peak at a little over 4.6.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python seaborn Package Guide</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-07-seaborn-package-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 15:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-07-seaborn-package-guide/</guid>
      <description>A simple guide on how to make basic plots using the seaborn package from Python</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m learning data visualization in Python and I see myself as a &lsquo;hands on&rsquo; learner, so I&rsquo;ll be reproducing some basic plots using <code>seaborn</code> package that you can use as a reference everytime you need to fresh up your memory.</p>
<p>At first is required that the packages are properly imported, after that I load the iris dataset.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">import</span> pandas <span style="color:#66d9ef">as</span> pd
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">import</span> seaborn <span style="color:#66d9ef">as</span> sns
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#f92672">import</span> matplotlib.pyplot <span style="color:#66d9ef">as</span> plt
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>url <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;https://git.io/JXciW&#34;</span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>iris <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> pd<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>read_csv(url)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>If you&rsquo;re not familiar with the iris dataset, you can see its first five rows below:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>sepal_length</th>
<th>sepal_width</th>
<th>petal_length</th>
<th>petal_width</th>
<th>species</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>5.1</td>
<td>3.5</td>
<td>1.4</td>
<td>0.2</td>
<td>setosa</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4.9</td>
<td>3.0</td>
<td>1.4</td>
<td>0.2</td>
<td>setosa</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4.7</td>
<td>3.2</td>
<td>1.3</td>
<td>0.2</td>
<td>setosa</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4.6</td>
<td>3.1</td>
<td>1.5</td>
<td>0.2</td>
<td>setosa</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5.0</td>
<td>3.6</td>
<td>1.4</td>
<td>0.2</td>
<td>setosa</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="barplots">Barplots</h2>
<p>To create simple barplots.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>barplot(x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;species&#34;</span>, y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>, data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/barplot_EGCCNkum4y.jpg?updatedAt=1636308224965" alt="seaborn barplot species x petal_width"  />
</p>
<p>Making a horizontal barplot.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>barplot(x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>, y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;species&#34;</span>, data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/horizontal-barplot_pcHXoAQWTH.jpg?updatedAt=1636308226028" alt="seaborn barplot horizontal species x petal_width"  />
</p>
<p>Custom bar order.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>barplot(
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;species&#34;</span>,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    order<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>[<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;virginica&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;setosa&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;versicolor&#34;</span>])
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/barplot-custom-order_hUl5vUQOi.jpg?updatedAt=1636308225481" alt="seaborn barplot custom bar order"  />
</p>
<p>Add caps to error bars.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>barplot(x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;species&#34;</span>, y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>, data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris, capsize<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#ae81ff">.2</span>)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/barplot-cap-error-bar_xD7fHewAZ.jpg?updatedAt=1636308225172" alt="seaborn barplot caps error"  />
</p>
<p>Barplot withough error bar.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>barplot(x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;species&#34;</span>, y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>, data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris, ci<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#66d9ef">None</span>)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/barplot-no-cap-error_5sf2jPDpBag.jpg?updatedAt=1636308225717" alt="barplot no error bar"  />
</p>
<h2 id="scatterplots">Scatterplots</h2>
<p>A simple scatterplot.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>scatterplot(x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;sepal_width&#34;</span>, y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>, data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/scatterplot_nj8frw1JV.jpg?updatedAt=1636308224619" alt="seaborn scatterplot"  />
</p>
<p>Mapping groups to scatterplot.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>scatterplot(x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;sepal_width&#34;</span>, y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>, data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris, hue<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;species&#34;</span>)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/scatterplot-grouped_JHOKt9xydY.jpg?updatedAt=1636308224802" alt="seaborn scatterplot grouped"  />
</p>
<p>Mapping groups and scalling scatterplot.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>scatterplot(
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;sepal_width&#34;</span>,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    hue<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;sepal_length&#34;</span>,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    size<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;sepal_length&#34;</span>)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/scatterplot-grouped-size_mZJt-TjEv.jpg?updatedAt=1636308224806" alt="seaborn scatterplot grouped size"  />
</p>
<h2 id="legend-and-axes">Legend and Axes</h2>
<p>To change the plot legend to the outside of the plot area, you can use <code>bbox_to_anchor = (1,1), loc=2</code>. The following plot has a custom title, a new x axis label, and a y axis label.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span style="display:flex;"><span>sns<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>scatterplot(x<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;sepal_width&#34;</span>, y<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;petal_width&#34;</span>, data<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>iris, hue<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;species&#34;</span>)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>plt<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>legend(
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    title<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Species&#34;</span>,
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    bbox_to_anchor <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> (<span style="color:#ae81ff">1</span>,<span style="color:#ae81ff">1</span>),
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    loc<span style="color:#f92672">=</span><span style="color:#ae81ff">2</span>)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>plt<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>xlabel(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Sepal Width&#34;</span>)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>plt<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>ylabel(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Petal Width&#34;</span>)
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>plt<span style="color:#f92672">.</span>title(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Sepal Width x Petal Width&#34;</span>)
</span></span></code></pre></div><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://ik.imagekit.io/devmedeiros/python_seaborn/title-axis-outside-legend__zUIAf_2427.jpg?updatedAt=1636308224813" alt="seaborn scatterplot outside legend with custom title and axis labels"  />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
