<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Dev_Medeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Dev_Medeiros</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.com/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:49:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Challenge - Churn Rate</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-05-30-churn-rate-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:49:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2022-05-30-churn-rate-challenge/</guid>
      <description>I was challenged to take the role of a new data scientist hired at Alura Voz. This made-up company is a telecommunication company and it needs to reduce the Churn Rate.
The challenge is divided into four weeks. For the first week, the goal was to clean the dataset provided by an API. Next, we need to identify clients who are more likely to leave the company, using data exploration and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptive Analysis of Amazon Top 50 Bestselling Books 2009 - 2019</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-12-28-amazon-top-50-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 14:55:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-12-28-amazon-top-50-books/</guid>
      <description>Recently I finished an Alura course named Python for Data Science and I want to put what I learned into practice, to do so I&amp;rsquo;ll make a descriptive analysis on this dataset Amazon Top 50 Bestselling Books 2009 - 2019. It contains 550 books and the data has been categorized as fiction and non-fiction by Goodreads. All of the code can be found here.
I started checking the first five observations from the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python seaborn Package Guide</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-07-seaborn-package-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 15:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/2021-11-07-seaborn-package-guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m learning data visualization in Python and I see myself as a &amp;lsquo;hands on&amp;rsquo; learner, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be reproducing some basic plots using seaborn package that you can use as a reference everytime you need to fresh up your memory.
At first is required that the packages are properly imported, after that I load the iris dataset.
import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns import matplotlib.pyplot as plt url = &amp;#34;https://git.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
