<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ethic on devmedeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.com/tags/ethic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ethic on devmedeiros</description>
    <image>
      <title>devmedeiros</title>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 08:01:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.com/tags/ethic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making Better Graphs</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/choose-the-best-graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 08:01:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/choose-the-best-graph/</guid>
      <description>Choosing the best graph or plot can be a hard task, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Learning how to make better visualizations come with study and practice, today I want to talk about sources you can use to guide you into making better graphs and other data visualizations in general.</p>
<h2 id="from-data-to-viz">From Data to Viz</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://i.imgur.com/416qeWj.png" alt="infograph showing different possibilities for choosing a plot"  />
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.data-to-viz.com/">From Data to Viz</a> brings a lot of tools to help navigate the data visualization world. In the website <code>Explore</code> tab you are faced with an interactive infographic that helps you pick a plot, you can choose between: <code>numeric</code>, <code>categoric</code>, <code>numeric&amp;categoric</code>, <code>maps</code>, <code>network</code>, and <code>time series</code>. But it doesn&rsquo;t only show plots that would be good for your type of data, it also shows a description explaining the plot and common mistakes people make when using that specific plot.</p>
<p>At the end of each branch from the infographic, there is also a <code>story</code> link, where you can read about an implementation of that type of plot using real-world data.</p>
<p>And in the case, you are just starting and don&rsquo;t know many terms or are unsure if your data contains <code>too many</code> or <code>few</code> points when you rest your mouse over the options nodes you&rsquo;ll be able to see a description with an example table representing what that means.</p>
<p>By heading to the <code>Caveats</code> tab you&rsquo;re able to see a collection of caveats, you can filter them by:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Improvement:</strong> all caveats that will suggest some sort of improvement on plots.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Misleading:</strong> some plots may be misleading by omitting some information, may it be sample size or how proportionally different two categories are. By reading this you&rsquo;ll be able to spot bad practices that lead to confusion or manipulation.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This website also provides links to <strong>Python</strong> and <strong>R</strong> galleries where you can get code snippets to reproduce these plots.</p>
<p>If you prefer to learn by looking at what not to do, you should check out <a href="https://viz.wtf/">WTF Visualizations</a>. It showcases bad visualizations that don&rsquo;t make sense or are somehow misleading.</p>
<p>There you&rsquo;ll find several pie plots that don&rsquo;t add up to 100%, area graphs where the numbers don&rsquo;t match the area, and just straight-up manipulation like the example below.</p>
<figure class="align-center ">
    <img loading="lazy" src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/d8bcf748d564125312aeba4001b96df5/tumblr_qzg4n3nfJY1sgh0voo1_640.jpg#center"
         alt="a donut graph showing &#39;yes&#39; as a majority while it represents 10%, and &#39;no&#39; as a minority while it represents 90%"/> <figcaption>
            <p>piechart from <a href="https://viz.wtf/">WTF Visualizations</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/ethics-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 16:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/ethics-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Data Science is an exciting field, but it&amp;rsquo;s also full of ethical dilemmas.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>Data science is an exciting field, but it’s also full of ethical pitfalls. If you want to avoid getting drawn into a situation that could damage your company or client, it’s important to understand the basics of data ethics and how they can affect your work.</p>
<h2 id="learning-from-the-past">Learning from the past</h2>
<p>Learning from the past is important because it can help us avoid making ethical mistakes that others already committed. The following examples are a sampling of some of the most popular data science ethics issues over the years:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Google&rsquo;s Street View privacy concerns (2011)</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>In 2011, Google came under fire for collecting personal data from unsecured wireless networks while taking pictures for its Street View service. The company said it was an accident and that it had not intended to collect any information from these Wi-Fi networks. However, computer security experts discovered a code in the software used by Google&rsquo;s cars that indicated that they were designed to do just that.</p>
<p>Google said it had collected data like emails and passwords, but it wasn&rsquo;t sure how much. The fact that Google didn&rsquo;t know what data was collected raised concerns about its commitment to user privacy and security.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Facebook&rsquo;s Cambridge Analytica scandal (2018)</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>In March 2018, Facebook revealed that it had been the victim of a massive data breach involving tens of millions of users. The company said that Cambridge Analytica, a political consultancy firm with ties to the Trump presidential campaign, had gained access to information from up to 87 million.</p>
<p>Users were unaware that the app was collecting data from them, and Facebook did not do enough to prevent it. The incident led to intense scrutiny of Facebook&rsquo;s use of user data and its responsibility for protecting users&rsquo; privacy. In April 2018, Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg testified before American Congress on the matter. He apologized for his company&rsquo;s mistakes in handling user data and outlined some steps he would take to ensure that similar breaches didn&rsquo;t occur again.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>IBM’s Photo-scraping scandal (2019)</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>IBM faced a photo-scraping controversial scandal in 2019 where the controversy focused on 1 million pictures of human faces that IBM scrapped from Flickr, the online photo-hosting site.</p>
<p>This scandal brought to light how their data is being used. People aren’t consenting to have their details used for profit.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Predictive Policing Software</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>It would be nice to be able to predict crime or be able to estimate where law enforcement needs to be to prevent crime, but many predictions made by this kind of software don’t come true. This happens because these tools are fed bad data.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Data collected by police is notoriously bad, easily manipulated, glaringly incomplete, and too often undermined by racial bias.” – <a href="https://www.aclu.org/news/criminal-law-reform/predictive-policing-software-more-accurate">Ezekiel Edwards, ACLU</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This polluted data makes the software produce equally contaminated results, leading the software to be better at predicting policing instead of predicting crime, becoming a self-fulfilling prophecy.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>These examples show that there are many ways to make mistakes when it comes to handling user data, but they also serve as excellent educational resources for anyone interested in learning more about <em>how</em> these kinds of problems can be avoided in future projects.</p>
<p>There are lots of resources to learn more about this theme and how to combat this issue when working with machine learning models and user data. I&rsquo;ll list some, but remember this is a broad and deep topic, and my research may not find everything there is to it.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://geomblog.github.io/fairness/">A free course on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency sponsored by GIAN.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bXitS_PMyFQ">Why Mathematicians Won&rsquo;t Help Cops - VSauce2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/data-ethics-framework/data-ethics-framework-2020">Data Ethics Framework - UK Government</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
