<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>knowledge on devmedeiros</title>
    <link>https://devmedeiros.com/tags/knowledge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in knowledge on devmedeiros</description>
    <image>
      <title>devmedeiros</title>
      <url>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</url>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:32:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devmedeiros.com/tags/knowledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Analysis for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/multivariate-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:32:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/multivariate-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The two most important multivariate analysis techniques for data science.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-is-multivariate-analysis">What is Multivariate Analysis?</h2>
<p>Multivariate analysis is a branch of statistical methods that allows analyzing the distribution of two or more variables. In statistics it can be used to reduce the dimensionality of data, simplifying variability, or for inference techniques.</p>
<h2 id="principal-component-analysis">Principal Component Analysis</h2>
<p>Principal Component Analysis, also known as PCA, constitutes a multivariate analysis method whose purpose is to reduce the dimensionality of data. This reduction occurs by reducing the number of columns or variables while maintaining a significant percentage of the variability present in the data.</p>
<p>The use of this technique becomes interesting when dealing with a large number of variables of interest that you want to group and correlate. For example, a telecommunications company may have various information about its customers, such as age, income, profession, length of service with the company, and products/services purchased, among others. Often, the analyst wants to take advantage of all this information, whilst avoiding <em>overfitting</em>. In this context, the application of PCA emerges as a valuable tool, allowing dimensionality reduction while preserving the intrinsic variability of these variables.</p>
<h2 id="cluster-analysis">Cluster Analysis</h2>
<p>Cluster analysis, also called clustering, is a technique that aims to group individuals or variables with similar characteristics. There are several algorithms for clustering, but the most common and most used is K-means.</p>
<p>Clusters can be used to create metrics and indices that can be used to evaluate a business or even to build forecasting models.</p>
<p>These tools are fundamental for scientists and analysts seeking to extract valuable <em>insights</em>, avoid <em>overfitting</em>, and promote a deeper understanding of the structure of multivariate data.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Up with the Latest in Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://devmedeiros.com/post/keeping-up-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 20:51:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devmedeiros.com/post/keeping-up-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>How to keep up with the latest discoveries in Machine Learning Models and academic research.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every day new research regarding Machine Learning is being published, and it may seem impossible to keep up with all the new models and applications that people are using. So I want to talk about my two favorite ways to keep up with new research and know about what people are working on.</p>
<h2 id="1---two-minute-papers">1 - Two Minute Papers</h2>
<p>This YouTube <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TwoMinutePapers">channel</a> is my favorite one to keep up with new research regarding Machine Learning. They are always releasing new videos talking about papers showing what researchers have just published, focusing mainly on the results, but always linking the original paper so you can read more about it.</p>
<p>Two Minute Papers have been covering the OpenAI discoveries for quite some time now, I remember seeing videos about what ChatGPT could do, before it was open to the public, and it compared it with previous versions. So you can see the progress being made, even if you miss the older videos, they always make a comparison with previous versions when available.</p>
<p>The videos are kept in an approachable language, so even beginners can understand the main points. Additionally, the channel also makes the videos entertaining, so it&rsquo;s easy to keep watching and stack on more knowledge.</p>
<h2 id="2---papers-with-code">2 - Papers with Code</h2>
<p><a href="paperswithcode.com">Papers with Code</a> is more than a website that just indexes papers. It makes it easier to find papers with code about Machine Learning, linking the papers, the source code, and even datasets.</p>
<p>If you want to learn about the state-of-the-art of a specific topic in Machine Learning you can browse between tasks, for example, if you are looking for more information about Natural Language Processing, you can choose a specific task, like Named Entity Recognition, then you&rsquo;ll be able to see the current benchmarks, according to database, the best model, the model paper and source code. It also links the databases used to research the specific task you choose and it links libraries that you can use to apply the models.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
